This is one of the most obscure authors
in American literature, L.H. Anderson,
who wrote Ancient Magic, Magnetism, and
Psychic Forces in 1895, published from
the Masonic Temple in Chicago. Try and
Google some information on L.H.
Anderson. He talks about hypnotism, mind
control, and explains the Earth in
magnetic and electrical principles. You
can't find anything on this guy, and
[music] I think I know why. I'm going to
read it to you and draw a diagram that
explains it. God has been spoken of as
the grand electrical focus, and he has
[music] been appropriately styled as the
mind of all minds. the source or found
from which all minds emanate like
[music] streams from a great reservoir.
The further a mind is from the grand
focus, the less it will be impressed.
So, persons who are greatly elevated and
refined are more easily, correctly, and
wisely impressed or inspired. The form
of a wheel furnishes a good [music]
illustration. This is our wheel. Notice
it's a circle like the Earth. Let the
hub represent the focus. The hub is what
will be God. And the spokes radiating
lines from that focus. And then we have
spokes [music] radiating all the way
out. Along these lines may be supposed
to be located minds in different stages
of elevation as they are nearer or more
remote from the center. There's
different minds, and some are located
closer to source than others. The
further an individual is from the grand
focus, the more intermediate links or
minds [music] a thought or impression
must pass through to reach him, and the
more minds the thought flows through,
the more imperfect and less reliable is
the impression it makes upon the
terminal mind. Well, all thought and
inspiration [music] flows from God, and
that we're all positioned further or
closer to the central focus. Therefore,
[music] the thoughts and inspiration of
our minds will be more or less diluted
depending on our location to God. We're
going to say, "Oh, Jesus is right here.
Joe is right here." Suppose it is
determined to reach a mind of a low
order. The thought to be transmitted
passes through, say, 12 minds [music]
before it reaches that particular
individual on the Earth through whom it
is to be impressed. What is received by
the 13th and has [music] been greatly
modified. The Bible's been changed. It's
been modified. Why? Because the thought
flowing from God that went to Jesus was
then passed through a number of men
>> [music]
>> before it got to you. He's explaining
what we know the Bible has been altered
and you're receiving [music] polluted
and diluted information. Thus mind is
constantly affecting mind and higher
always controlling the lower. This is a
universal law. You see it happening
right now. The big fighting the small
all of us feeling the tension the pool
and [music] all we've got to do is get
the impurities out of our mind and you
can't help where you were born along
this wheel but you can damn sure move
closer by cleaning yourself up. I'm in
the process of reading more but wanted
to come in here and show you what blew
my mind so hopefully it can clear yours.